So I want to show you how authenticated
encryption is used in the real world, so
我想演示如何在现实生活中运用认证加密技术
let's use TLS as an example and see how
TLS works. So data encryption in TLS is
让我们以TLS做为例子 并看看它是如何工作的 TLS中的数据加密
done using a protocol called a TLS record
protocol. In this protocol, every TLS
是通过使用TLS记录协议完成的 该协议中 每个TLS
record starts with a header, we'll see the
structure of the header in just a minute,
记录以一数据头开头 不久我们就会看到这个数据头的结构
followed by encrypted data that is sent
from one side to the other. In TLS, it so
紧接着是从一端到另一端的加密数据 TLS中
happens that the records are at most
sixteen kilobytes and if more data than
记录的长度至多为16KB 如果需要
sixteen kilobytes needs to be sent, then
basically the record is fragmented into
发送多于16KB数据 那么该记录就会分割成
multiple records. Now TLS uses what's
called unidirectional keys, meaning that
多个记录 TLS运用的是单向密钥
there's one key from browser to server,
and there's a separate key from server to
即一密钥从浏览器到服务器用 另一个密钥从服务器到浏览器使用
browser. So one key is used for sending
messages from a browser to the server, and
所以 一密钥供浏览器到服务器发送消息使用
the other key is used from sending
messages from the server to the browser,
另一密钥用于服务器到浏览器发送消息
and of course both sides, both the server
and the browser, know both of these keys.
当然 浏览器端与服务器端相互知道这两个密钥
And just to be clear I'll say the browser
will use this key to send data to the
为了更好理解 我这样假设 浏览器使用这个密钥发送数据给
server and we'll use this key to read data
from the server and the server basically
服务器 那我们使用该密钥从服务器读取数据 这里服务器也
does exactly the same thing just with the
opposite keys. Now these keys, both of
使用另一个密钥做相同操作 而这些
these keys are actually generated by the
TLS key exchange protocol which we're
供两端使用的密钥都是由TLS密钥交换协议产生的
gonna talk about in the second part of the
course. Right now I'm gonna assume that
该协议将在本节的第二部分讲到 现假设
these keys have already been established.
They're known to both the server and the
已创建了这些密钥 且服务器端与浏览器端都知道这些密钥
browser, and now the browser and server
want to exchange information using those
现在服务器和浏览器试图使用这些密钥交换数据
keys. So the TLS record protocol uses
what's called stateful encryption, which
那么TLS记录协议就会使用状态性加密 也就是
means that the encryption of every packet.
Is done using certain state that's
每一数据包都是使用由浏览器和服务器内部维护的
maintained inside of the browser and the
server. In particular the state that's of
特定状态来加密的 特别地 更能吸引我们的是
interest to us are these 64 bit counters,
again there are two 64 bit counters. One
64比特计数器 再次强调 有两个64比特计数器
for traffic from browser to server, and
one from traffic from the server to the
一个用于浏览器到服务器的信息流 另一个用于服务器到浏览器的信息流
browser. These counters are initialized to
zero when the session is first
当这些计数器第一次初始化时值为0
initialized, and they're incremented every
time a record is sent. So every time the
并且每次发送记录后 计数器的值都会增加 所以每当
browser sends a record to the server, the
browser will go ahead and increment this
浏览器发送一记录给服务器 浏览器都会增加计数器的值
counter. When the server receives that
record, it'll go ahead and increment the
而当服务器接收记录后 它也会增加
counter on its side. And when the server
sends a record to the browser, he'll go
它这边的计数器值 而当服务器发送一记录给浏览器 它就会
ahead and increment the second counter and
again when the browser receives this
增加第二个计数器的值 此外 当浏览器接收到这个记录后
record it'll go ahead and increment its
copy of this counter. So this state these
它就会增加它的计数器的值 这个状态即两个计数器
two counters basically this state exists
both on the browser and on the server and
既存在于浏览器上也存在于服务器上
it's updated appropriately as records are
sent from one to the other and received
此外它随记录从一端发送到另一端而更新 并且
by the appropriate side. Now the purpose
of these counters as we'll see in just a
被适当的接收方接收 这些计数器存在的目的是
minute is to prevent replay attacks so
than an attacker can't simply record the record
防止重放攻击 这样攻击者就不能记录消息
and then replay at a later time because by
then the counters will have to be
并在之后的时间内重放 因为这时计数器将不得不增加
incremented. Okay, so let's look at the
details of how the record protocol works.
现在我们来看记录协议的工作细节
In particular I'll show you kind of the
mandatory cipher suit which is encryption
特别地 我会演示强制密码组 也就是加密使用AES―CBC
using AES-CBC and MACing using HMAC-SHA1. Okay,
so remember, TLS uses a MAC, then encrypt,
杂凑使用HMAC―SHA1 记住 TLS使用杂凑算法 然后加密
where the MAC algorithm is HMAC-SHA1, and the encryption
而这个杂凑算法就是HMAC-SHA1 而加密算法
algorithm is AES128 in CBC mode. Okay, so
let's look at how the browser sends data
是使用AES128的CBC码 现让我们看看浏览器如何发送数据给
to the server, which, as I said, is done
using the browser to server key. Now, the
服务器 前面说过 它是通过使用浏览器到服务器的密钥实现的
browser to server key itself, is made up
of a MAC key and an encryption key. Two
而这个浏览器到服务器密钥是由一杂凑密钥与一加密密钥组成而成
separated keys that are again as I said
negotiated during session setup. And again
两不同的密钥均是在会话建立时协商的 为了使你们
I wanna be absolutely clear. There is a
separate key for browser to server and a
完全明白 解说如下 一独立密钥供浏览器到服务器使用
separate key from server to browser. So
there, overall, there are four keys. Two
另一密钥供服务器到浏览器使用 所以2*2共4个密钥
MAC keys, and two encryption keys, each
one used in the appropriate direction.
两个杂凑密钥和两个加密密钥 每个密钥都在合适的地方使用
Okay, so here I wrote down the diagram of
what a tls packet looks like. It begins
然后 这里我图示出了一TLS数据包的结构 它以一数据头打头
with a header that contains the type of
the packet, the version number for the
该数据头包含有数据包类型、协议版本号
protocol, and the length of the packet.
Notice the length of the packet it sends
数据包长度等信息 注意数据包长度以明文发送
in the clear. Now, when encrypting
data, a certain record, the encryption
而当要加密数据也就是一特定记录时 加密步骤如下
procedure works as follows. Of course, it
takes key as input, and it takes the
当然 它以密钥、当前状态等做为输入
current status input. And then it works as
follows. What it'll do is first of all is
接着 它首先
it would MAC the following data, while
here's the actual payload that's MACed but
对这个数据进行散列计算 这个是要计算散列值的实际有效载荷
the heather is also MACed. In addition the
counter, the current value of the counter
而数据头也需要进行散列计算 此外 计数器 也就是计数器的当前值
is also MACed and of course, it's all the
counters implemented during the
也需要进行散列计算 当然计数器的值会随着
key fact that one more record has
been sent. Now the interesting thing here
发送一记录而增加 这里有趣的是
is that even though the value of the
counter is included in the tag. You notice
虽然计数器的值包含在特征值中 但可以注意到
the value of the counter is actually never
sent in the record, and the reason it
计数器值不会包含在记录中被发送
doesn't need to be sent in the record is
that the server on the other side already
而不需要包含在记录中被发送的原因是在另一端的服务器已经
knows what the value of the counter needs
to be. So it doesn't need to be told in
知道计数器的值 所以不需要再次告诉
the record what the value of the counter
is. It implicitly already knows what it
服务器端计数器的值 服务器私底下是知道它的值的
is, and when it's gonna verify the MAC, it
could just use the value that it thinks
并且当服务器想要认证杂凑值时 它可以用它自己认为的
the counter should be and verify the MAC
in that fashion. Okay, so this is kind of
计数器值然后完成认证 比较有趣过程是
an interesting approach, where even though
the two sides maintain these counters that
即使两端都保存有作为临时数的计数器的值
function as nonces, there is no
reason to send the nonces in the record,
两端依然不需要将临时值包含在记录中发送
because both sides actually already know
what counters they're expecting every
因为两端都知道它们所接收的记录的计数器值
record that they receive. Okay, so that's
the tag. The tag is computed, as we said,
所以这个就是特征值 它是通过这三重数据计算出来的
over this triple data. The next thing that
happens is that the tag is concatenated to
接下来 特征值会串联在这些数据上
the data. Remember, this is MAC-then-Encrypt. So here, we computed the MAC. Now
记住是先计算散列值后加密 这个是计算的散列
we're gonna encrypt the data along with
the tag. So the header, the data, and the
接下来将数据与特征值一起加密 所以数据头、数据、和特征值
tag are padded to the AES block, and I
think we already said that this pad, if
会被填加到AES数据分组上 我想我们前面已经讲过这个填充
the pad length is five, then the pad is
done by simply writing the byte five, five
如果填充长度为5 那么填充就是将字节5重复写5次
times. If the pad link leads to be 5, the
pad would just be 55555. And then we CBC
如果填充的是5那么整个填充就是55555 接着我们使用密钥
encrypt using the encryption key, we CBC
encrypt the data and the tag. And we do
利用CBC加密方法加密数据与特征值 加密过程中
that using a fresh random IV, which is
later embedded in the cipher text. And
使用一个新随机数IV 该数之后会被嵌于密文中
then we prepend the header, the type,
the version and the length. And that gives
接着 我们来考虑数据头 也就是类型、版本、长度
us the entire TLS record, which is then
sent over to the server. So the grayed out
以上就是整个TLS记录 最后被送给服务器
fields in this diagram correspond to
encrypted data, and the white fields
整个图中蓝色区域表示加密数据 白色区域
correspond to plaintext data. So you can
see that this is TLS's implementation of
表示未加密明文 以上就是TLS应用的
MAC then encrypt. The only difference from
basic MAC then encrypt is the fact that
散列与加密计算 与普通MAC不同的唯一之处是
there is a state, namely this counter is
being included in the value of the MAC.
它含一个状态值 也就是MAC值中包含的计数器值
And again as I said that's done to prevent
replays. So let's see why that prevents
这是为了防止重放攻击 为什么这样能防止重放攻击
replays. In particular, let's see how the
record protocol decrypts an incoming
我们来看记录协议是如何解密记录的
record. So, here comes an incoming
encrypted record. And again, the server is
假设这里有一个加密记录 当然 服务器会
going to use it's own key that corresponds
to data, from browser to server. And it's
使用从浏览器到服务器的秘钥得到对应的数据
own browser to server counter. And the
first thing it's going to do, is it's
并启动从浏览器到服务器的计数器 然后 服务器首先会
going to decrypt the record using the
encryption key. After encryption, it's
使用加密密钥来解密这个记录 解密后 服务器会
going to check the format of the pad. In
other words, if the pad length is five
检查填充的格式 如果填充长度是5字节
bytes, it's going to check that it really
is five, five, five, five, five. And if
它就会检查填充是否是55555 如果不是
it's not, it's gonna send a bad record mac
alert message and terminate the
服务器就会发送错误警告消息并终止链接
connection. So that a new session key will
have to be negotiated if more records need
如果想要另发送记录 就需要协商新的会话密钥
to be sent. If the pad format is correct,
then removing the pad is really easy. All
如果填充格式是正确的 那么移除填充就很简单
the server does is it looks at the last
byte of the pad, say the last byte is
由服务器观察填充的最后几字节 如果最后几字节等于5
equal to five, and, then, it removes the
last five bytes of the record. By doing
然后服务器移除最后5字节的记录
that it strips off the pad. The next thing
it's gonna do is it's gonna extract the
这样就可以移除填充 接下来 服务器会取出
tag from the record. So, this would be the
subsequence bytes inside of the record.
记录中的特征值 在记录中后面的字节
So, this would be the, the trailing bytes
in the record after we remove the pad, and
它在我们移除填充后的最后的字节
then it's gonna verify the tag on the
header, the data and its value of counter.
接着服务器检查特征值中的数据头、数据、计数器值等
And if the Mac doesn't verify again, it's
gonna send an alert, bad record Mac, and
如果这个散列值不能通过认证 服务器会发送警告和错误散列值记录并
tear down the connection. And if the tag
does verify, it's gonna remove the tag,
中断链接 如果特征值通过了认证 服务器会移除特征值
remove the header, and the remaining part
of the record is the plain text data
移除数据头 留下来的记录部分就是数据明文
that's given to the application. Now, you
can see if a record is ever replayed, in
这部分就是待发送给应用的数据 现在你应该了解到 如果记录被重放
other words if an attacker records a
particular record and then replays it to the
换句话说 如果一攻击者记录了一个特定记录并在之后的时间
server at a later time, then, by then the
value of the counter would have changed
将其重放给服务器 那时计数器的值已经被改变
and as a result the tag on the replayed
record would simply not verify because the
结果就是 重放记录的特征值就不会通过认证
tag was computed using one value of the
counter but when the replayed record as
因为特征值是使用计数器计算出来的 但当重放记录被服务器接收时
received at the server The value of the
counter of the server is different from
服务器的计数器值与上次用来计算特征值的
the value that was used to compute a tag
and as a result the tag was not verified.
计数值不同 结果通不过认证
So these counters are very elegant and
simple way for preventing replays and the
所以这些计数器是非常简便的防止重放攻击的方法 而且
nice thing about this is because both
sides know the value of the counter implicitly
由于两端均知道计数器的值
there's never a need to send the
counter in the record itself. So the
所以没有必要将计数器包含在记录中发送 所以
counter itself doesn't increase the length
of cipher text L. Now, we already
计时器不会随着密文的长度L增加 现在我们已经
mentioned that this particular approach
to, authenticated encryption, namely, MAC,
提到这种特殊的方法，认证加密，即 先做MAC
then encrypt, using CBC encryption, is, in
fact, authenticated encryption. However,
后加密，使用CBC加密方式 实际上 就是认证加密 但是
it's only authenticated encryption if no
other information is leaked during
它仅仅是在加密时没有信息泄露的情况下是认证加密
decryption. And we're going to see some
acute attacks on TLS if there is
泄露。我们讲一种对TLS严重攻击，如果在
information being leaked during
decryption. I should say that this bad
解密过程中有信息泄露。这个
record MAC alert basically corresponds to
the decryption algorithm outputting this
错误记录的MAC警告相当于解密算法中输出的拒绝符号也就是⊥符号
reject symbol, the bottom symbol. Meaning
that the cipher text is invalid. And as
这就意味着密文是无效的
long as there's no way to differentiate
between why the cipher text was rejected,
只要没有办法区分密文为何被拒绝
in other words the decrypter only exposes
the fact that a rejection took place but
即解密者只暴露了发生了拒绝这样一个事实但又
it doesn't say why the rejection happened
this is in fact an authenticated
没说明拒绝为什么发生 这其实就是一个认证加密系统
encryption system. However, if you
differentiate and expose why the cipher
然而 如果你区分并暴露了密文
text was rejected whether it was because
of a bad pad or because of a bad mac then
为何被拒绝 不管是因为错误的填充或者是因为错误的MAC
it turns out there's a very acute attack.
Which we're gonna see in the next segment.
那么这就是将在下一部分讲到的一个十分严重的攻击
What I showed you so far is called TLS
Version 1.1. It turns out that earlier
到目前我所展现的是1.1版本的TLS 实际上
versions of TLS actually had significant
mistakes in it, and as a result, the
更早版本的TLS存在重大的错误 结果就导致
earlier Record Protocol is vulnerable to a
number of attacks. The first mistake is
先前的记录协议容易受到各种攻击 它的第一个错误是
that the IV used in CBC Encryption is
predictable. And we said earlier that in
CBC加密算法中的IV是可预测的 我们之前说过在CBC中
CBC, if the IV is predictable then the
resulting CBC Encryption is not CPA
如果IV是可预测的 那么将导致CBC加密算法不是CPA安全的
Secure. Well, in this older version of
TLS, TLS 1.0 and earlier, the IV for the
在旧版本的TLS 比如在TLS1.0或者是更早的版本中
next record is simply the last cipher text
block of the current record. And as a
下一个记录的IV就是当前记录的最后一个密文分组
result, if the adversary can observe the
current record, he knows the IV for the
这就导致如果攻击者能够观察出当前记录 那么他就知道下一个记录的IV
next record and that will allow him to
break the semantic security of the next
这就让他能够破坏下一个记录的语义安全
record. So the resulting scheme is not CPA
secure. But not only is it not CPA secure,
于是最终的方案不是CPA安全的 这样的方案不仅不是CPA安全的
in fact, there is a very acute attack
called a BEAST attack that's able to decrypt
而且  还有一种能够解密TLS记录起始部分的被称为BEAST的攻击方式
the initial part of the TLS record
simply based on the fact that this scheme
就是因为这个系统不是语义安全的
is not semantically secure. So, I should
say that this method of choosing the iv to
这种选IV来做前一个记录的最后一个分组的方法
be the last block of the previous record
is called chained iv's. And you should
被称为链IV
remember that this, actually should not be
used in practice because it always, always
你们应当记住这种方法不应该被用于实践 因为它总是
leads to an attack. Because of this TLS
1.1 moved to what's called, explicit iv's
被攻击 由于TLS从版本1.1发展到了被称为外显IV
where every TLS record has its own random
unpredictable iv. And that's fixed the
每一个TLS记录都有自己的随机不可预测的IV的版本
problem as soon as browsers and servers
move to TLS 1.1, this will no longer be an
只要浏览器和服务器使用TLS1.1 问题就能被解决 而且这永远不会出现问题
issue. Now another mistake that was done
in TLS 1.0 and earlier, enabled what's
另一个TLS1.0和更早版本的错误就是
called a padding oracle. Which is
something that we're going to talk about
启用了一个被称作Oracle填充的的东西 我们将在下一部分来讨论Oracle填充
in the next segment, were what happened
was, that if the cipher text was rejected
Oracle填充就是如果密文
due to an invalid pad The server was sent
back an alert message saying decryption
因为无效填充而被拒绝的话 服务器就会收到一条
failed. Whereas if the cipher text was
rejected due to a bad Mac, the server will
解密无效的信息 然而 如果密文是因为无效的MAC而被拒绝的话 服务器就会回复
send back a bad record Mac alert. As a
result, and adversary who observes the
一个无效记录的MAC的警告 所以
alert sends back from the server, can tell
whether the pad in the cipher text was
观察服务器回复警告的攻击者能够分辨出密文中的填充是有效还是无效的
valid or invalid. And this introduces a
very significant attack called a padding
这就引入了一种十分重要的被称为填充攻击的攻击方式
attack, which we're gonna talk about in
the next segment. The solution to this and
我们将在下一部分讨论这种攻击 对于这种攻击和TSL1.1的解决方案
TLS 1.1, was basically to say that,
instead of reporting decryption failed
基本上就是 即使填充是错误的
here, we're gonna report a bad record Mac,
even if the pad is incorrect. And, as a
也只报告一个错误记录的MAC 而不报告一个失败的解密
result, simply looking at which alert is
sent back from the server, an attacker
所以 仅仅观察服务器送回的警告
can't tell if a cipher text is rejected
because of a bad pad or a bad MAC. So this
攻击者是不能分辨出密文是由于错误的填充还是错误的MAC而被拒绝的
tries to mask this information. Now the
lesson from this is that when decryption
这就是说 我们从中汲取的教训就是当解密失败时
fails, you should never ever explain why,
I guess this is something that comes out
你永远不要去解释为什么  我想这是一种源自于网络协议中的东西
of networking protocols where if there is
a failure you wanna tell the peer why the
如果出现了一个错故障 你就想对你的伙伴解释故障出现的原因
failure occurred, where in cryptography if
you explain why the failure occurred that
而在密码学中 解释故障出现的原因常常会导致被攻击
very often leads to an attack. In other
words when decryption fails just output
换句话说 当解密失败时直接输出拒绝
reject and don't explain why the reject
actually happens just reject the ciphertext.
不要去解释拒绝为什么会发生 直接拒绝密文就可以
Okay, so now that we've seen TLS 1.1,
let's see a broken protocol. So of course
我们讨论过了TLS1.1 现在来看一个被破解的协议
I always like to pick on 802.11b WEP,
which pretty much got everything wrong. So
当然我挑基本上什么都是有问题的802.11b WEP来做例子
let's see how not to provide authenticated
encryption. So let me remind you how
让我们来看一下如何不要提供认证加密 先让我提醒下你们802.11b WEP
802.11b WEP works. Basically there's a
message that the laptop wants to send to
是如何工作的，一个笔记本电脑想要给
the access point. The first thing that
happens is it, the laptop computes a
一个接入点发送一条信息 首先 笔记本电脑会计算
cyclic redundancy checksum on the message
and concatenates the CRC checksum to the
一条信息的循环冗余校验和并且把CRC校验和与这条信息连接在一起
message. Then the result is encrypted
using a stream cipher, in particular RC4.
然后结果用流密码加密 例如RC4
If you recall, the key that's used is the
concatenation of an initial value IV
如果你还记得的话  使用的密钥是
that changes per packet and the long term
key K. And then the IV along with the
每一个包都会变化初始值IV的连接和一个长效密钥K 然后IV和密文一同
cipher text are transmitted to the other
side. Now we've already saw two
被传输到了另一端 我们之前已经讨论过了
problems with this approach. One was if
the IV is ever repeated and in fact it is
这种方法的两个问题 一是如果IV被重复使用的话
gonna be repeated then you get a two time
pad attack. And the other problem
你就会受到两次一个两次填充攻击 另一个问题是
is that [inaudible] uses very closely
related keys. In other words, the key is
使用关联紧密的密钥 换句话说 密钥是
simply IV concatenated to K and the only
thing that changes are the IV so the key
IV与K的串接 唯一发生改变的就是IV 所以
is always fixed, which means that these
PRG keys are very closely related to one
密钥一直都是固定的 这意味着 这些PRG密钥互相之间
another and as we said, the PRG that's
used here, RC4 is not designed for this
联系很紧密 像我们前面说的 这里用了PRG RC4 不是设计来这么用的
type of use and it completely breaks
if you use it with related keys, and as a
如果你用相关密钥的话 它就完全被攻破
result WEP has no security at all.
What I want to show you. Is that even the
因此 WEP根本不安全 我想证明给大家的是
crc mechanism that's used here. In an
attempt to provide integrity and prevent
即使这里用到了CRC机制 试图提供完整性 防止
an adversary from tampering with the
cipher text, even that mechanism is
敌手篡改密文 即便这种机制
completely broken, and it's actually very
easy to tamper with cipher texts en route.
被完全攻破 实际上在传输中是很容易篡改密文的
So let's see how that's done. The attack
uses a particular property of the CRC
让我们看看这个怎么做 攻击利用了CRC校验的的一种性质
check sum. Mainly the CRC is linear. What
that means is if I give you CRC of M, and
主因是CRC是线性的 这意味着如果我给你m的CRC校验码 我
I ask you to compute CRC of M XOR P, then
it's very easy to do. Basically you'll
要求你计算m异或p的CRC，很容易 基本上你户
just compute some well known and public
function of F(P), you XOR these two together,
计算公开的函数F(p)你先异或这两个
and that in fact will give you CRC of
M XOR P. So it [inaudible] the xor comes out
这样就会给你m和p异或的CRC校验 所以异或
of the parenthesis, and that basically
means the CRC is linear. Now here is how the
就从这个括号里出来了，意味着CRC是线性的 现在我们看看
attack works, suppose the adversary
intercepts a particular, packet that's
攻击是怎么进行得 假设敌手截获了一个特定的包
destined to the access point. Now the
packet say, sais it's destined for
这个包是发往接入点的 现在这个包，令其目的
destination port 80, and the attacker
knows that it's intended for destination
是80端口 攻击者知道它要发往
port 80 and what he wants to do is
modify the cipher texts such that now the
80端口而且他想篡改这个密文使得目的端口
destination port will say 25 instead of
80. And maybe the attacker can read
变成25而不是80 攻击者可能能够读
messages for port 25 and that's how he
actually obtains the actual data in the
25端口的信息 这样他实际上就得到了这个包中的数据
packet. So recall that the CRC checksum
is there to make sure that exactly the
回忆CRC校验在这里是为了保证
attacker cannot change data inside of the
cipher text. But I want to show you that
攻击者不能改变密文中的数据 但是我想说明 实际上
in fact it's really easy to modify data in
the cipher text and CRC basically provides
想改变密文中的数据十分容易 CRC
no security against tampering at all. So
let's see how to do it. Well, what the
实际上根本不能对篡改提供安全性 让我们看看如何进行
attacker would do is, he would basically
Xor some, a certain value XX into the byte
好，攻击者 基本上就是一些特定的值XX
that represents the eight zero in the
cipher text. Now what he'll Xor in will
和代表密文中的8个0的字节异或 现在 他就是
basically be the string 25 Xor 80 and you
remember that if I Xor a certain string XX
把25和80进行异或 再与密文中特定的串XX进行异或
into the cipher text. That was created
using a stream cipher. When that cipher
这个是用来做流密码的 当密文
gets, is decrypted, the plain text at this
position will also be Xored by XX. And as
被解密 这个位置的明文将被XX异或
a result after decryption the plain text
at this position basically will be the
结果就是解密后这个位置的明文就是
original 80XR 25 XR 80 which gives us 25.
Okay? So after decryption the plain text
原始的80异或25异或25，结果就是25，对吧？
of this position will now be 25. The
problem is that if that's all we did then
所以解密后这个位置的明文将是25 问题是 如果我们就这么做
this attack would fail because the CRC
check sum would now would not validate.
这个攻击不会成功 因为CRC校验在这里就不成立了
The CRC check sum. Was built with 80 as a
plain text but 25 is a different plain
CRC校验 是对80这个明文建立的，25是
text and needs a different CRC. But it's
not a problem because what we can do is we
另一个明文需要另外一个CRC校验 但是这也不是问题 因为我们能做的是
can easily correct the check sum, the CRC
check sum, even though the CRC check sum
仅仅校正一下校验和 CRC校验和 虽然CRC校验和
is encrypted. What we do is we XOR
F of XX into the cipher text at the place
是被加密了。我们就是异或F(xx)到密文的这个位置
where the CRC is supposed to be and as a
result, when the cipher text is decrypted
这里应该是那个CRC 结果就是 密文被解密的时候
what will happen is we'll get the correct
CRC check sum after decryption. So, the
在解密后我们就能得到正确的CRC校验和
interesting thing that happened here is
even though the attacker doesn't know what
这里有意思的是 即便攻击者不知道
the crc value is, he's able to correct it
using this linearity property such that
CRC值是什么 他可以利用线性性质校对是的
when the cipher text is decrypted the
correct crc value appears in the plain
密文被解密为明文时，能得到正确的CRC值
text. Okay? So the linearity property of
CRC plays a critical role in making this
所以，CRC的线性性质在这个攻击中起到了重要的
attack works. The end conclusion here is
basically that a CRC check sum provides
作用 这里最终的结论是CRC校验绝对不能提供
absolutely no integrity at all against
active attacks and it should never, ever,
完整性，在针对主动攻击的情况下 因此永远
ever be used as an integrity mechanism.
And instead if you want to provide
不要用它作为一种完整性机制 所以为了提供完整性
integrity you're supposed to use a
cryptographic mac not an ad hoc mechanism
你应该用一种密码MAC体制而不是随便什么机制
like CRC. Okay, so now we've seen how
authenticated encryption is implemented in
比如CRC 好，现在我们了解了在现实世界中的协议中认证
a real world protocol, like TLS. In the
next segment, we're gonna look at real
加密是怎样使用的，比如TLS 下一节 我们将讨论
world attacks on authenticated encryption
implementations that happen to implement
一下现实的攻击，尤其是在认证加密在没有被正确使用
authenticated encryption incorrectly.
的情况下，对认证加密的攻击。